<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="34"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[A Letter from the Editor




        I
           t is with great pleasure and honor that I write this first letter to
           introduce “Shikorr -Magazine” and me, it is a new beginning

        of an auspicious era of my life. Shikorr -Magazine basically it

        will  be  a  souvenir  –  magazine  for  particular  group  of  Shikorr

        member- community, but it will also publish as a quarterly all the

        year- long for staying connected to our friends and well–wishers.  Shikorr -Magazine, it’s a

        new magazine but a promising one. This magazine is dedicated to bring simple, accessible and

        amusing articles. We are looking forward to spot light you, your experience, and your passion,

        what makes you unique. Writing is an absolute and individualistic act, but the importance of

        sharing your work can’t be ignored. A personal essay or writing can bind you to an aspiring

        audience. If you are a full-time freelance writer or an enthusiast essayist, eager to publish your

        work for the first time, you can finally stop stressing you can submit your work to us, we will

        take care of it for you. And our harmonious and familiar Shikorr ally groups, they are really

        special to us, like our own family; We are eagerly waiting to cover their issues, events and

        their passions, hobbies, passionate writings. we will try our best to rejuvenate Shikorr groups,

        and associations up to their ultimate level. Sometimes people slip unnoticed, under the radar,

        sometimes people, groups and experiences don’t receive the spotlight, the acknowledgement,

        or the media coverage they should get. Our goal is to cover all of them, serve them all in a best

        possible way.  The world is changing noticeably; this is the era of rapid change we are living

        in now, let’s try to change together, try to share our experience, our untold stories together

        with our friends and allies, at the end I am finishing with a William Shakespeare’s quote – “To

        Mingle Friendship Far is Mingling Bloods.”


        Best Regards


        Fouzia Nishat Sultana


        Editor, Shikorr Magazine]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[GENERATIONS KNOW HOW
             BEAUTY AND FASHION WITH






                                                                  4








                                          Artificial Intelligence the


                                                          Inevitable Future
                                                                                      15









                                                                   GREEN JAMS

                                                                                            19




                                                     RHAPSODY OF HER EYE'S


                                                                                             32










                                                                              গল্পে আবি
                                                                                              ২৪












             কবিতার প্রহর                                রন্ধন

                             ২৭                                            ২৯]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[eauty and Fashion with





          B            Generations Know How (Part One)

                        Fouzia Nishat Sultana







                            Conceptions encircling beauty and ideal look not only vary


        by culture, but also have developed significantly throughout generations.


        People were eagerly chasing beauty and ideal look for centuries. Fashion]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[and  beauty  are  BFF’s;  they  can  stand  on  their  own,  but  are  better

        together.  Fashion  is  one’s  distinctive,  signature  look.  It  is  one’s  own


        personal  style.    Beauty  in  the  realm  of  fashion  can  be  described  as


        characteristics or attributes that lead to harmony, balance, attraction,


        and  well-being.  Tradition  of  beauty  care  and  fashion  trend  always


        changed  with  the  change  of  generations.  A  generation;  to  define    a


        generation in short is "all of the people born and living at about the same


        time, have similar characteristics and behaviors, a collective group of


        entities that share or motivated by at least one common issue or interest,


        or work together to achieve a common objective. Generational changes

        challenges key values and ideas that help define the prevailing situations;


        Generational  conflict  arises  whenever  the  interests  or  ideals  of  one


        generation  collide  openly  with  those  of  another.  Wars  and  economic


        dislocations always have been regarded as generation-defining events.


        Twentieth century was the era of turmoil and change, war and economic


                                                                                            th
        depression;  there  were  rapid  generational  changes,  20   century  was

        divided  into  six  consecutive  generations.  Previously  centuries  were

                                                                                                               th
        usually  divided  into  two  to  three  generational  cohorts,  but  the  20

        century  it  was  a  different  era,  the  two  greatest  war  of  the  history  of


        mankind  World  War  1  and  World  War  2  changed  everything.


        Modernization  of  beauty  care  and  the  modernization  of  fashion  trend


        twentieth century is the period that saw the most rapid and revolutionary


        changes so far. World War I is the most important single event in the


        world history; it became known as the Great War, because it affected


        people all over the world as no conflict before World War 1 had caused]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[destruction on this scale before. It destroyed empires, created numerous

        new  nation-states,  encouraged  independence  movements  in  Europe's


        colonies, forced the United States to become a world power and led Soviet


        Union directly to communism, the destabilization of European society,


        laid the groundwork for World War II. During the World War I trend of


        clothing were dictated more by necessity than fashion. As more and more


        women  were  forced  to  work,  they  demanded  clothes  that  were  better


        suited to their new activities. These two biggest war of the world, World


        War 1 and World War 2 totally changed people’s life, economic turmoil


        followed by depression had a grave impact on the society. New ideas were

        imposed; new type of life style was incorporated. Each generation had


        different likes, dislikes, and attributes. The six living generations, which


        are six fairly distinct groups of people, From the 1920s to the 1990s,


        popular  fashions  reflected  the  mood  of  each  decade  and  showcased


        changes in society as the styles of clothing and accessories evolved with


        the times. Each generation has different experience, emotions and sense


        of style. Name of these generations are:



            1. The Greatest Generations (born 1901s- 1927s)


            2. The Silent Generations (born 1928s- 1945s)


            3. Baby Boomers (born 1946s- 1964s)


            4. Generation X (born 1965s- 1980s)

            5. Generation Y (Gen Y) Millennials (1977s-1995s)


            6. Generation Z, or Gen Z (born 1995s-2010s )]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[The  Greatest  Generation:  Greatest  Generation  also


        known as the  G.I. Generation  or the  World War II generation, is the

        demographic cohort following the  Lost Generation and preceding  the


        Silent  Generation.  They  are  the  oldest  living  generation  now.  This


        generation is generally defined as people born and grew up from 1901 to


        1927. They were shaped by the Great Depression and were the primary


        participants in World War II. The women of this era began to enter the


        professional world, found a new need to wear more make-ups, women


        publications such as the French Beauty Industry encouraged women to


        wear  makeup  to  look  their  best  while  competing  with  men  for

        employment.  The  introduction  of  makeup  was  reasonably  new  to  the


        society.  Women  were  figuring  out  methods  to  apply  it  correctly.  The


        beauty ideal of the 1920's had heavily defined eyes with dark eye-makeup.


        Kohl  was  used  to  line  the  eye  and  achieve  an  overall  dramatic  look.


        Cosmetics were characterized by their use to create a specific look: lips


        painted in the shape of a Cupid's bow, and bright cheeks brushed with


        bright red blush, heavily made-up look of the 1920s was a reaction to the


        demure, feminine look of the pre-war period. It was the time when an


        international beauty culture was forged, and society increasingly focused

        on novelty and change.  The effect of World War 1 was so much visible


        in the fashion sector, as clothes were in short supply and rationed, older


        clothes were transformed into modern styles. Many women wore short


        skirts and sensible 'flat heeled' shoes. It was very unusual to see women]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[wearing trousers. The outbreak of war changed the roles of women in

        society leading to the need for a different kind of fashion, more structured


        military look entered in the fashion sector because of jobs often requiring


        a uniform or trousers. As women dressed for new roles, gender-dictated


        dress  codes  relaxed.  Skirts  became  shorter,  as  they  often  do  during


        wartime, and colors became sober and muted. Skirts were simple shapes


        with  a  mid-calf  tea-length.  Details  such  as  white  side  buttons,  large


        pockets, and wide gathered waistbands matched those of dresses. The


        skirt sat high on the waist in which a blouse or “shirtwaist” was tucked


        into and billowed out slightly. These skirts looked almost like a longer,

        more flowing version of the pencil skirts of today. They were often worn


        with a tunic, jacket, or even a fur-lined coat. The popular colors were for


        women: peach, grey, blue, rose, yellow, sand and black. For men: navy,


        grey, green, and brown.









                              Next The Silent Generation or the Traditionalists was the


        demographic cohort following the Greatest Generation and preceding


        the  baby  boomers.  This  relatively  small  generation  found  itself

        sandwiched  between  the  war  hero  G.I.s  and  the  large  and  influential


        Baby  Boomer  generation,  Silent  Generation  is  generally  defined  as


        people born from 1928 to 1945, who were children during World War II



        and too young to fight. The “silent generation” so called because they

        were  raised  during  a  period  of  war  and  economic  depression.  The


        generation was comparatively small because the Great Depression of the]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[1930s and World War II in the early-mid 1940s caused people to have

        fewer children. It includes most of those who fought during the Korean


        War.  They  are  noted  as  forming  the  leadership  of  the  civil  rights


        movement as well as comprising the "silent majority". They went through


        their formative years during the Great Depression and its aftermath. The


        Silent Generation has much fewer savings priorities and tends of think of


        their finances in terms of the rest of their lives. They are the most likely


        group to express a lack of financial stability. Silent generation facts have


        shown that individuals of this time were either part of or born during


        World  War  II,  and  many  of  them  focus  on  salvaging  valuables  and

        finances. They steer away from wastage and places significant value on


        economic resources. The Silent started out as the children of crisis.  They


        grew  up  while  older  people  were  fighting  wars  and  making  great


        sacrifices on their behalf.  They were the mature group. It was the time


        of economic uncertainty, financial restrictions, ongoing difficulties, and


        lack of modern luxuries. But still The Silent Generation followed meekly


        in the shadow of the GI Generation. They adopted the GI Generation’s


        art, music, clothing, and overall culture. 1930s which began with G.I.s

        were defined by pencil thin eyebrows. Plucking eyebrows became very


        popular, and heavy kohl eye makeup gave way to a more feminine lighter


        shades.  Max  Factor  introduced  their  first  cream  eye  shadow  and  lip


        gloss. Women in the 30s followed a beauty routine each day that required


        a number of different products. Most women used cold cream to cleanse


        their  face  (soap  was  still  widely  used,  but  was  seen  as  harsh  for  the


        delicate skin of the face); it was oil based and could wipe away the grime]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[from the skin without leaving the skin dry. Women would apply a thin

        layer and wipe it away with a soft cloth. This would be followed by a


        number of creams and tonics to even out fine lines and wrinkles. Women


        were  encouraged  to  keep  a  still  face  to  avoid  developing  lines!


        Contouring came in for the first time in the ‘30s, women would define


        their  cheekbones  using  blusher  underneath  them  and  coourful  eye


        shadows were used. Sunbathers in the ‘30s were so anti-freckle that they


        would wear a freckle-proof cape to avoid sun damage. Chemist Franz


        Greiter came along to invent sunscreen in 1946.Well-established beauty


        moguls  Helena  Rubinstein  and  Elizabeth  Arden  leading  the  industry,

        more salons began opening and ushered in a variety of new anti-aging


        treatments.  For  a  perfectly  flushed,  youthful  complexion,  the  glamour


        bonnet and other helmet-like structures came into fashion. Rosy cheeks


        were also sought after via electronic heated face masks, skin-tightening


        wraps  and  vacuums  aimed  at  addressing  issues  like  sagging  skin,


        circulation and acne. Now the fashion trend of Silent Generation, the


        women  had  abandoned  the  boyish  look,  they  favored  clothes  that


        accentuated the natural waistline and fitted more closely to the body.

        Narrow  hips,  however,  were  still  greatly  desired.  The  economic


        hardships of the era led to the rise of cheaper factory-made clothing,


        particularly  garments  featuring  zippers.  But  evening  dresses  were  all


        about  glamour;  silky,  clingy,  bias-cut  dresses  showed  off  a  woman's


        figure. As for men in the '30s, they wanted to be Superman – literally. An


        athletic figure was greatly sought after, and clothes emphasized broad


        shoulders and narrow waists. Military-inspired jackets and coats were]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[popular, as were high-waist, pleated pants. As for evening wear, tuxedo

        tailcoat was the must-have look. But after mirth during 1940s, women


        started wearing knee-length dresses. They also began wearing shoulder


        pads under their dresses, blouses and jackets, creating a boxy, masculine


        appearance. It wasn't uncommon for women to remake men's suits into


        women's wear while the men were overseas fighting in World War II.


        Cleavage was a no-no, but women's clothing did feature cut-outs and


        sweetheart necklines. The apparel of this era was less geared towards


        fashion and more towards durability. Men commonly wore suits, sport


        coats, trousers, and sweaters during the '40s. The typical outfit consisted

        of dress pants and shirts. They also opted for fitted sweaters, sweater


        vests, and waistcoats. The clothing was meant to emphasize their figures.











                                Baby boomers are the demographic cohort following the

        Silent  Generation  and  preceding  Generation  X.  The  generation  is


        generally defined as people born from 1946 to 1964, during the post–


        World  War  II.  The  baby  boom  has  been  described  variously  as  a


        "shockwave"  and as "the pig in the python." Baby boomers are often


        parents of late Gen Xers and Millennials.In the 1960s and 1970s, as this


        relatively large number of young people entered their teens and young


        adulthood—the oldest turned 18 in 1964—they, and those around them,

        created  a  very  specific  rhetoric  around  their  cohort  and  the  changes


        brought about by their size in numbers, such as the counterculture of the


        1960s, there was a movement of ‘’Single Girl’’. The idea of a Single Girl]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[in  the  1960’s  was  a  woman  who  was  on  the  move  young,  single,

        economically self –sufficient. In China during the same period, the baby


        boomers lived through the Cultural Revolution and were subject to the


        one-child policy as adults. This rhetoric had an important impact in the


        perceptions of the boomers, as well as society's  increasingly common


        tendency  to  define  the  world  in  terms  of  generations,  which  was  a


        relatively  new  phenomenon.  In  Europe  and  North  America,  many


        boomers came of age in a time of increasing affluence and widespread


        government subsidies in post-war housing and education, and grew up


        genuinely expecting the world to improve with time.











                                 In the 2020s, baby boomers in developed countries, with


        a few exceptions, are the single biggest cohort in their societies due to


        sub-replacement  fertility  and  population  aging.  Baby  Boomers  are

        currently  the  largest  generation  at  approximately  77  million  people


        (Generation  Y  runs  a  close  second.),  they  are  the  post-World  War  II


        generation.  They  are  the  member  of  the  demographically  large


        generation, and because of their numbers and the relative prosperity of


        the economy during their careers, the baby boomers are an economically


        influential generation. Hollywood stars such as Marilyn Monroe greatly


        influenced women's beauty standards in the 1950s. The hourglass shape


        and curvaceous figures were sought after, as was perfect skin. After the


        strict regulations of wartime, hyper-femininity became all the rage; when]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[out and about, women wore dresses and sweater sets and skirts. Their

        dresses  featured  wide  crinoline-puffed  skirts and  small  collars  with  a


        variety of designs on them. Closer-fitting dresses became more popular


        later in the decade. Men loosened up with their fashion in the '50s. They


        wore  Hawaiian  shirts,  trousers, and  loafers.  Polo  shirts  also  became


        popular both on the golf course and off. The younger generation wore


        cardigan sweaters and letterman jackets, white t-shirt and jeans – was


        relegated to the "bad boys." The economy was still strong in the 1960s,


        so fewer women made their own clothes, instead opting to shop for them.


        What people wore often indicated their social-class, and casual clothing

        became  the  standard.  Women  strived  to  be  thin,  aimed  for  the


        androgynous look. Women wore miniskirts and imitated British-inspired


        "Mod" fashion. Both men and women started wearing bright colors and


        clothes featuring geometric patterns. Men wore flared pants, knit shirts,


        and sweaters.  There was also rebellion against predecessors, women


        rebelled against wearing makeup and shape-defining articles of clothing,


        such  as  girdles,  padded  bras,  and  stockings.  Instead,  they  opted  for


        peasant  shirts,  tie  dye  garments,  bell-bottomed  jeans,  and  long  maxi

        skirts. Both men and women preferred wearing sandals and growing their


        hair long. Men also grew unruly beards. By the 1970s, people were less


        concerned  with  fitting  in  with  the  crowd  and  more  interested  in


        expressing their  individual personality through their clothing  choices.


        Leisure  suits,  overalls,  bell  bottoms,  tunics,  giant  collared  shirts,  and


        pant  sets  were  common.  People  also  wore  bright  colors  and  tactile


        fabrics, such as velvet and corduroy. Sparkling fabrics were perfect for]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[nights  out  at  the  disco.  Working  women  wore  power  suits  with  silk

        blouses. Fur was also a popular add-on to many outfits. Men and women


        often  wore  double  denim,  pairing  denim  shirts  with  denim  pants.


        Turtlenecks and belted tank tops were also in style. As far as the bodies


        under all those vivid fabrics, a more natural look was favored. Health


        rather than thinness became the focus.]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence the Inevitable Future






        A         rtificial intelligence (AI), is the intelligence demonstrated by machines,



                  basically  it’s  simulates  the  human  intelligence  in  machines  that  are

        programmed  to  think  like  humans  and  to  mimic  their  actions.  Although

        technological progress has been accelerating, but still it has been limited by the


        basic  intelligence  of  the  human  brain,  Human  Intelligence  aims  to  adapt  new

        environments by utilizing a combination of different cognitive processes, whereas


        Artificial Intelligence aims to build machines that can mimic human behavior and

        perform human-like actions. Computer science defines AI research as the study of


        "intelligent  agents",  in  a  recent  study  McKinsey  Global  Institute  predicts  that

        intelligent agents and robots could replace up to 30 percent of the world's current


        human labor by 2030.  AI will surely take over many routine tasks done by humans.

        AI can replicate labour activities at much greater scale and speed, and to even


        perform some tasks beyond the capabilities of humans. Not to mention that in some

        areas it has the ability to learn faster than humans, not as deeply yet. “Success in

        creating AI would be the biggest event in human history. Unfortunately, it might


        also be the last, unless we learn how to avoid the risks." Stephen Hawking.



        Artificial  intelligence  (AI)  gathered  momentum  after  Alan  Mathison  Turing

        developed  a  mathematical  model;  Turing's  most  notable  work  today  is  as  a]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[computer  scientist  in  1936,  he  developed  the  idea  for  the  Universal  Turing

        Machine, the basis for the first computer. And he developed a test for artificial


        intelligence in 1950, which is still used today.






        Today,  AI  has  grown  from  problem-solving  data  models  to  artificial  neural

        networks  -  a  computer  model  based  on  the  structure  and  functions  of  human


        biological  networks.  AI  is  changing  our  lives  at  a  phenomenal  speed.  From

        driverless cars to special purpose robots, AI is meant to enhance the quality of


        human lives. Technologies powered by AI and Machine learning have already

        began  transforming  the  industrial  landscape,  providing  organizations  with


        tremendous benefits and adding great value to their businesses. The sectors of

        transportation, healthcare, logistics, finance and industrial manufacturing, among

        a  plethora  of  others,  would  undergo  an  immense  transformation  under  the


        influence of AI and they would evolve to be more productive and cheaper and,

        more importantly, provide better services.


























        Among all its applications, I am most excited by the results that would be produced


        by AI in the following areas:]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Healthcare



        With the help of AI-powered expert systems and autonomous

        robot surgeons, the risk associated with all type of surgeries


        can be drastically reduced as even minor operations can be

        done with a remarkable degree of precision and efficiency.



        Research has already shown that deep neural networks can be trained to produce

        basic  radiological  findings,  with  high  reliability,  by  training  from  archives  of


        millions  of  patient  scans  collected  by  healthcare  systems.  Many  giants  have

        already entered the field of Healthcare robotics.



        Personal Care



        We already have several chat-bots and personal agents like Google home, Alexa,


        and Siri that are built to help us with our simple queries. In the near future, we

        might have humanoid robots that can perform our daily chores for us.



        The  great  advances  in  Natural  Language  Processing  and  Image  processing

        enabled by Deep learning will enhance robot’s interaction with people in their


        homes. Another area in which AI can be really helpful is Elder care.



        Autonomous Systems



        Over a period of time, all the jobs that endanger


        human life but are important can be carried

        out  by  AI  empowered  robots;  this  includes  fixing

        power lines, finding oil in the deepest ocean trenches and acting as a


        police force against crime.]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Agriculture




        Here’s an alarming fact, the world

        will  need  to  produce  50  percent


        more food by 2050 because we’re

        literally eating up everything! The


        only way this can be possible is if

        we  use  our  resources  more

        carefully. With that being said, AI


        can help farmers get more from the

        land while using resources more sustainably.



        Issues such as climate change, population growth, and food security concerns have


        pushed the industry into seeking more innovative approaches to improve crop

        yield.



        Organizations  are  using  automation  and  robotics  to  help  farmers  find  more

        efficient ways to protect their crops from weeds.



        “Our intelligence is what makes us human, and AI is an extension of that quality.”

        – Yann LeCun Professor, New York University.



        AI will have a dramatic impact on human society. Artificial intelligence has acted

        as the main driver of emerging technologies like big data, robotics and IoT, and it


        will continue to act as a technological innovator for the foreseeable future.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[GREEN JAMS SPEAR MINT



        Tania Akter
        S


                             pearmint is a wide-spreading perennial herb; it is highly aromatic and is

                             both refreshing and uplifting to the mind. Spearmint is truly unique in many

                             aspects,  from  its  flavor  to  its  appearance.  It  is  widely  cultivated  for

        medicinal, culinary, and beauty uses, can be used fresh, dried, or frozen to flavor tea, cold

        drinks,  and  sauces.  It  is  also  known  to  help  with  digestion  and  fever.  The  scented  oil  in

        spearmint is also used as an essential oil that goes by the name of 'oil of spearmint.' This is

        frequently used as an ingredient in shampoos, shower gels, and toothpastes, mouthwashes,

        and cosmetics. It is often used in medicine for its claimed therapeutic properties. Spearmint

        also known as garden mint, common mint, is a species of mint, and the scientific name is

        Mentha Spicata.



        Different Uses of Spear Mint:
         Spearmint or Mentha spicata is a pleasant-smelling species of mint.


        It  has  various  types  of  uses  from  health-food  products,
        beauty  –  home  refreshment  products,  it  always  have


        soothing  and  pleasing  presence  in  everywhere.  It  is
        used  in  medicine  for  its  claimed  therapeutic


        properties,  with  its  anti-bacterial  properties;

        Spearmint  is  believed  to  make  an  ideal  skin

        cleanser.  By  imparting  a  cooling  sensation,

        Spearmint  Oil  can  help  to  relieve  itching

        associated with dryness and skin irritations.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Here Are Some Ways to Use Fresh Mint:

        1.Make Your Own Mint Tea to Aid Digestion

        Use 5-10 big leaves or more depending on how strong you want it. Tear the leaves and place

        in a mug, then muddle the leaves for a few seconds

        with  the  back  of  a  wooden  spoon.  Pour  hot  (not

        boiling)  water  over  the  leaves  and  let  steep  5-10

        minutes. You can remove the leaves or leave them in

        (punny!) – I leave them in and eat them as I sip.


        2. Change up Your Protein Smoothie


                                                   Add 3-4 fresh
                                                    mint  leaves  to


                                                    your  chocolate  protein  smoothie  for  a  delicious
                                                    variety. I love ice, water, chocolate protein powder,


                                                    flax seeds, and mint whipped up in the blender. Mint is
                                                    wonderful in berry smoothies, too.



                                                    3. Make a Minty Lime Fizzler

                                               Muddle 5-8 mint leaves

        in the bottom of a glass. Add ice, a healthy squeeze of lime

        and club soda with a few drops of stevia to sweeten. (Is it

        5 o’clock somewhere? Turn this into a low-sugar mojito by

        adding an ounce of white rum if you so please.)


                                              4. Make My

                                                Watermelon

                                                Mint Pops

                                                Homemade  popsicles

                                                are  an  easy,  healthy,  and

                                                delicious treat. These pops require only 4 ingredients and

                                                you will love them, with watermelon, spearmint, little bit

                                             lemon juice and little bit honey needed to make popsicles.]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[5. for Water and Beverages

        Add fresh mint to plain or sparkling water, or even freeze

        whole  leaves  in  ice  cubes  to  add  beautiful  color  to  your

        beverage. Or,



         Make Mint Ice Cubes

                                            Freeze  whole  mint  leaves

                                               into  ice  cubes  for  a

                                               pretty      (and      tasty)

                                               addition  to  your  water.

                                               Place  2-3  small  whole  mint  leaves  (or  a  few  torn  large

                                               ones) into an ice cube tray, add purified water and freeze.

                                               If you boil the water your ice cubes will be crystal clear;

                                               let it cool to room temp before adding it to your ice cube

                                               trays.






        6. Salad Ingredient:
        Chop up a few leaves and add them to salad along

        with some freshly grated ginger and lemon zest. The

        flavor combo is amazing and adds a great summery

        flare to salad.]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Different Health Benefits of Spearmint:


        Spearmint  is  used  to  improve  memory,               Drinking  spearmint  tea  may  help  reduce

        digestion,  stomach  problems,  and  other              hair growth, or growth of dark, coarse hair

        conditions, but there is no good scientific             on the face, chest and abdomen of women.

        evidence to support these uses. The oil in
                                                                5. May Improve Memory
        spearmint  contains  chemicals  that  reduce

        inflammation (swelling) and change levels               There’s some evidence that this herb may

        of  chemicals  called  hormones,  such  as              help improve memory.

        testosterone, in the body. Some chemicals
                                                                6. Fights Bacterial Infections
        might  also  harm  cancer  cells  and  kill
                                                                Spearmint is a popular flavoring agent in
        bacteria.
                                                                toothpaste, breath mints and chewing gums.

        1. Good for Digestive Upsets                            Spearmint has antibacterial activity against

        Spearmint is commonly used to help relieve              several types of harmful bacteria, including


        symptoms of indigestion, nausea, vomiting               bacteria  that  cause  foodborne  illnesses,
        and gas. Abdominal pain and bloating.                   such as E. coli and Listeria.



        2. High in Antioxidants                                 7. May Lower Blood Sugar


        Antioxidants       are    natural      chemical         Spearmint tea may help lower blood sugar

        compounds found in Spearmint plants that                in people with diabetes.

        help  protect  against  and  repair  damage
                                                                8. May Help Reduce Stress
        caused by free radicals, which are harmful
                                                                Spearmint tea may help promote relaxation
        molecules that can lead to oxidative stress.
                                                                and  reduce  stress.  This  mint  contains

        3. May Aid Women with Hormone                           compounds  that  have  been  shown  to
        Imbalances
                                                                promote relaxation and reduce stress.

        For  women  with  hormone  imbalances,
                                                                9. May Improve Arthritis Pain
        spearmint tea may provide relief.

                                                                Spearmint  may  help  relieve  joint  pain
        4. May Reduce Facial Hair in Women
                                                                caused  by  arthritis  both  in  human  and

                                                                animal. Additionally, tea made from this]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[herb  may  help  reduce  stiffness

                                                                              and disability caused by arthritis.



                                                                              10. May Help Lower Blood

                                                                              Pressure


                                                                              Spearmint  may  help  lower  high

                                                                              blood      pressure;       it    works

                                                                              similarly  to  common  blood

                                                                              pressure medications.



                                                                              11. Easy to Incorporate Into
                                                                              Your Diet


                                                                              Spearmint        makes      a     great


                                                                              addition      to     any     diet     —

                                                                              particularly  in  the  form  of

                                                                              spearmint  tea,  which  can  be

                                                                              enjoyed hot or cold.



                                                                              12. For dry skin

                                                                              If you suffer from dry skin, mint

                                                                              leaves can help. All you need to

                                                                              do is grind them and squeeze the


                                                                              juice out of them. Apply this

                                                                              juice on your dry skin and see

                                                                              the results for yourself.



                                                                              In the end, Spearmint is a

                                                                              delicious, minty herb that makes

                                                                              a great addition to any diet.]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[জীবনে প্রথম নেবাচেী নিউটি





                                     ব




        মঈন খান

                            া
        জীবনন প্রথম ননব বচননর নিউটি নিল ফেব্রু/৯১ সানলর জাতীয় ননব বচন।তখন আমার চলনিল
                                                                                   া
        প্রনব: নপ্রয়ি। ফ ানটিং নিল রাঙামাটি। নিউটি নিল কাপ্তাই উ নজলার সব বনচ দূনরর এক দূর্ বম

                                                                  া
        ফসন্টানর।ফসন্টানরর নাম আজ আর মনন ফনই।ননব বচননর একনদন আনর্  ুনলশ লাইন ফথনক
        অস্র ইসুু করার সময় এমন এক  অস্র নদল, ফেিা চালাননা ফতা দূনরর কথা িনবও ফদনখনন।

        সারদায় ফিাি অস্র ফথনক এস,এম,জজ এবিং এল,এম,জজ  ে বন্ত চালাননার নশক্ষা আনি নকন্তু এিা

        ফকান অস্র!নকউ বনল বুিার্ান, নেনন অস্র ইসুু করনিনলন নতনন বলনলন,


        ---এিা এস,এম,জজ-র চাচনতা ভাই অথবা এস,এম,জজও বলনত  ানরন।

        ---এিা ফতা আনর্ চালাই নন। ফদনখও নন।


        ---বনলন কী সুার!তনব নচন্তা নাই এস,এম,জজ-র মনতাই অ ানরসন নসসনিম।


        ---বদলায় এস.এম,জজ ফদয়া োয় না?]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[ব
        ---ওসব নাই।আ নানদর এিাই ফনয়ার নননদশ।

        কী আর করা। একখান ঐ অস্র এবিং ৪০ রাউন্ড গুনল বুনে ননলাম।নকন্তু মুনসবত হনলা এিা

                                                                                                             ু
        কাাঁনে ফোলার ফকান নসনলিং  াওয়া ফর্লনা।ফশনে ফমািা সুতলী নদনয় ফবাঁনে বাবাজীনক কাাঁনে তনল

                                                                                                                 ু
        ননলাম। (অস্রিার িনব ফনি ফথনক ফেনি সবার বুোর জনু েুক্ত করলাম।)। আর হা, ফেনহত
         াননর  নথ োনবা তাই অনস্রর সনথ ফবাঁনে ফদয়া হনলা “ইজ্জত রনশ”।ভাবনিন এিা আবার নক?


        এিা  হনে  এক  হানতর  মত  লম্বা

        একখন্ড  বাাঁনশর  সানথ  ৫০/৬০


        েি  লাইলননর  দনি   ুচাননা
          ু
        দন্ড। েরুন ফকান কারনন, নবনশে


        কনর  শানন্ত  বানহনীর  গুনল  ফখনয়

        আ নন লাশ হনলন এবিং অস্রসহ


        িু   কনর   ানননত   নি  ি ু ব

        মারনলন।  এর র  হয়নতা  ৪/৫


        নদন  র আ নন  াননিানন ফখনয়

                              াঁ
                      ু
        মাশাল্লাহ  েনল  ফেন   হাত   া
        চারনদনক  িনিনয়,  দুনর  ফকাথাও

        ফভনস উঠনলন নকন্তু অনস্রর নক হনব? তখন এই ইজ্জত রনশ আ না আ নন খুনল োনব এবিং


        ইজ্জত বাাঁচানত এক মাথায় অস্র অনু মাথায় বাাঁনশর খন্ডটি নননয় ফভনস থাকনব।ভাবুন একবার

        অস্রনরর কত বি ইজ্জত!! ো হউক,উ নজলা সদর ফথনক নপ্রজাইনিিং অনেসার তার সানগা

         ানগা এবিং ফভানির সরঞ্জামানদ নননয় তবলিনি বাজার োনি এলাম।১০/১১িার নদনক েি েি


        শনে  ইজঞ্জন  চানলত  ফদশী  ফনৌকায়  লিবহরসহ  রওয়ানা  হলাম।ফ িনন   াহানির  আিানল


        তবলিনি  বাজার  অদৃশু  হনলা।  শানন্ত  বানহনীর  সযৎভাবু  আক্রমননর  অশানন্ত  বুনকর  নভতর

                                                                                       ূ

        ফজনর্ই রইল।চানরনদনক লক্ষু কনর একদম ফবাবা হনয় ফর্লাম। নক অ ব বননসনর্ বক দৃশু! এমন
        সুন্দর  নরনবশ জীবনন প্রথম ফদখা। ো বর্ বনা কনর বুোনত োওয়া ফবাকামী।ফিাি বি  াহাি,


        সবাই ফেন স্বে  ানননত র্া ি ু নবনয় েুানন বনসনি।আমানদর আর্মনন জলচর  ানখরা নবরক্ত


        হনয়  এনদক  ওনদক  উনি  োনে।  শান্ত  নির   ানননত  দার্  ফকনি  ফকনি  আমরা  এনর্নয়]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[চলনি।ফনৌকার একনেনয় োনিক েিেি শে  াহানি প্রনতধ্বনন হনয় নেনর আসনি। াহানির


        েুান ভাগানত ভাগানত এক সময় আমরা র্ন্তনবু ফ ৌৌঁিলাম। োনি নবনিআর এর এক সাদা


        দানি  ওয়ালা  সুনবদার  ইিংনরজীনত  আমানদর  অভুথ বনা  জানানলন।নতনন  ফবশীর  ভার্  সমনয়

                                                                                                      ু
        ইিংনরজজনত  কথা  বনল  প্রমান  নদনত  লার্নলন  নতনন  ইিংনরজী  জাননন।তার  চাকরী  আনি
        ৬মাস।তার নামিা ভ ুনল ফর্নি। রাতিা তার কুানেই কািালাম।সকাল সকাল র্াটি ফবাসকা


        নননয়  ফভাি  ফসন্টানর  হাজজর  হলাম।  চারনদনক  নবনিআর  ফজায়াননদর  ঈর্নলর  মনতা  তীক্ষ্


        দৃটিনত  াহারা নদনত ফদনখ  নরনিনতর ভয়াবহতা বুেনত শুরু করলাম।আমানদর মনেু শুে                                ু

        নপ্রজানিিং  অনেসার  বািংর্ালী  বানকরা  উ জানত।ফভািারাও  সবাই  উ জানত।শুেু   ুনলশ/

        নবনিআর  বাঙালী।  েতদূর  মনন   নি  ফভািার  নিল  ৩০০/৩৫০  মনতা।নপ্রজানিিং  অনেসার


                                                                                             ু
        আনর্ই কার্জ  নে সবার সাইন নসর্ননচার নননয় ফেলনলন।দু ুর ফবলা নবস্কি কলা নদনয় লাঞ্চ

        করলাম।৪িা নার্াদ ফভাি ফশে হনতই সব ননয়ম নীনত ফভনঙ, ফভানির েলােল না জানননয়,


        এক রকম ফলজ গুটিনয় ফনৌকায় উনঠ বসলাম।কারর্  নথ  াহানি  াহানি আনম বপ্রনিকসন
        ফননম  ফর্নল  চলাচল  এনেবানর  হারাম।ফনৌকা  রািংর্ামাটির  উনেনশু  চলনত  থাকনলা।ফভাি


                                                  ু
        র্ননা সমান তানল চলনলা।হঠাৎ মৃতুর আতঙ্ক নেনর েরনলা কারর্  নথর মনেুই সন্ধ্ুা হনয়
        ফর্ল।আনম বরা প্রনিকশন ফথনক অবশুই চনল ফর্নি।আমার সানথ অজ্ঞাত নামা অস্র আর নতন


        নস াহীর কানি .৩০৩ রাইনেল।জানননা আক্রান্ত হনল নক হনব।দুরু দুরু বুনক েখন তবলিনি

                                                ু
        ফ ৌিলাম তখন ফ নি রাক্ষনসর ক্ষো।অন্ধ্কানর ফমাম ফেনল তখনও গুনাগুনন চলনি।কত

        ফভাি  নিনিল মনন ফনই তনব আমানদর ফসন্টানর  াশ করনলন নদ িংকর তালুকদার। আর

                                                                           া
        ফশে হনলা মৃতুর সানথ লনকাচুরী ফখনল জীবননর প্রথম ননব বচনী দানয়ত্ব  ালন।
                        ু
                                    ু]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[বিশালতা

                                     প্রহর                                   ফারজেয়ানা ম াক্তাজের




                                      মহলাল
                                                                                                      ু
                                                                       কখজনা কী কাজরা  ন মছাোঁজয়ছ তম ?
                       লিাম্প মপাজের মসামডয়া  আজলাজত
                                                                                 সমতি কজর বল।

                      মহেজলর পত্র পল্লব মববর্ ণহজয় উজেজছ।
                                                                         আচ্ছা, সাগর মছাোঁজয়ছ কখজনা?
                            েমিজর্র ে কা হাওয়ায় –
                                                                                তম  হয়ত বলজব
                                                                                  ু
                    আ ার  ুজখায়ব  েুজে আজলা – আবছায়ার
                                                                     মকন প্রায় হাোঁটি সাগজরর মবলাভ ু ম  ধজর,
                                মবভাগী আলপনা।
                                                                     হাোঁিজত হাোঁিজত কখজনা পামনজত পা ড ু বাই
                          আ ার আম ত্বজক মিজর আজছ –
                                                                               মসিা কী মছাোঁয়া নয়?
                           হাশুজনির অজ াি অনাম শা,
                                                                                               ু
                                                                       মসিা মতা অনিরক  অনভ ু মতর মখলা
                    আস াজনর স স্ত নিত্রজক তজল বমসজয়মছ
                                                  ু
                                                                            সাগর েজল পা মভোজনা।
                                 আপন মখয়াজল।
                                                                  সাগজরর মবশালতা তার গভীর মেজক গভীজর মক
                         তারপজরও ধ্রুব তারািাজক আে –
                                                                              অনুভব মসিা মছাোঁজয়ছ,
                         অজনক মবশী েুিমত য় মেখাজচ্ছ।
                                                                            নিাও মত মন অথে সাগর
                            জন হয়, আ ার অশ্রুপাত –
                                                                            কখন মক ভাজব? মক চায়?
                             তার খুব ভাজলা মলজগজছ।
                                                                            তা মকউ বুঝজত পাজর না।
                                লাগুক তাজত কী!
                                                                               তাই বলমছ মতা াজক
                        আ ার হৃেজয়র কাোঁচা রক্ত মেজয় মে,
                                                                         কখজনা কী কাজরা  ন মছাোঁজয়ছ?
                                আরও কজয়কিা –

                           রা ায়ন – মরাম ও মলখা োজব,
                                                                                   #ফাজরােী
                               তা কী মকউ োজন?

                             না োনজত মচষ্টা কজরজছ।

                                  আম জতা শুধু –

                              মতা াজক োনাজত চাই।

                            েীবজনর স স্ত সপ্ন মেজয় –

                                আে অি ণি বুজনমছ,

                         কজষ্ট েন্ত্নার প্রহর মকজি মগজলই

                                     ু
                        মতা ার মেবতলি চরজর্ অঞ্জমল মেব
                         মতা ার মচাজখর েলজক ধুজয় মেব


                           আ ার মচাজখর পামন মেজয়।।]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[ততািার জনয

                      ভাল্পলািাসা

                                                                                   হেলাল


                  ফারজেয়ানা হ াক্তাজের

                   আম  মতা ায় ভাজলাবামস                                           ম মেলাল,
                                                                                            ু
                                                                 আকাজশর তারাগুজলাজক তজল এজন হয়জতা
                  কোিা  ুজখ বলজত হয় না,
                                                                      মতা ার কপাজল বসাজত পারব না,
                                    ু
                    ওিা হৃেজয়র অনভ ু মত ।                                                           ু
            এক হৃেয় হজত অনি হৃেজয় মপ ৌঁজছ োয়                    মকন্তু, শরজতর শুভ্র-ক ল কাোঁশফল এজন

                                                                    মতা ার কপজল মছাোঁয়াজত পারব টেক ই।
                       মিমলজপমের  ত,
           স ান ভাজব েখন েুেজনই চায় েুেন মক                          ভরা পূমর্ ণ ার চাোঁেজক আম  হয়জতা
                         টেক তখন।                                   মতা ার আোঁচজল এজন মেজত পারব না,
                                                                 মকন্তু, তার স্বত ্ঃদ্বীপ্ত স্নীগ্ধ নীল মোছনায়


                                                                     মতা ার গা খামন মভজেজয় মেব টেকই।
                ুজখ বলজলই কী ভাজলাবাসা হয়?                         সাগজরর েলরামশজক আম  কখজনাই –
                                                                    মতা ার চরজর্ লুটিজয় মেজত পারব না,
             আজগর মেজন এই "ভাজলাবামস" কোিা
                না বজলও একেন মক একেন                         মকন্তু, তার মকাল হজত এক আোঁেলা পামন এজন,

                                                                     মতা ার পা েু’খামন ধুজয় মেব টেক ই।
                    ভাজলাবাসত আেীবন।
              এই কোিা েখন মেজক চালু হজয়জছ                          ম ি ালা হজত এক পশলা বৃটষ্ট এজন
               তখন মেজকই ভাজলাবাসািা ভাজে                           মতা াজক  াজতায়ারা করজত পারব না,
                                                                মকন্তু, মসানালী ধাজনর শীজে মশমশর কর্াজত
                   কাোঁজচর  তন েখন তখন।

                                                                       মতা ার মশহরর্ োগাজবা টেক ই।

                     ভাজলাবাস প্রান ভজর                          মগাধূলীর রটিন নীমল া এজন আম  হয়জতা
                                                                      মতা ার  নজক রািাজত পারব না,
                মেোয় স জঝাতা ও সহ ম  ণতা                           মকন্তু, প্রোপমতর উষ্ণ স্পজশ ণ আম
                  সজব ণাপমর মবশ্বাস মেন োজক
                    এজকর অপজরর প্রমত।।                               মতা ার  নজক রািাজত পারব টেক ই।
                                                                                            া
                                                                     পব ণজতর খরজরাতা ঝর্ ণ ধারা মেজয়

                                                                       আম  েু্ঃখ  ুজছ মেজত পারব না,
                                                                    মকন্তু, আ ার েু’মচাজখর েল মেজয়

                                                                 মতা ার েু’মচাজখর েলজক ধুজয় মেব টেক ই।
                                                                  স্বগ ণ হজত শামির অম য় অনামবল প্রবাহ
                                                                    মতা ার অিজর বইজয় মেজত পারব না,
                                                              মকন্তু, আ ার বুজক ভাজলাবাসার মরাত মস্বনী মেজয়
                                                                                                  োঁ

                                                                                                  ু
                                                                মতা ার বুজক সুজখর মফায়ারা ফিাজবা টেক ই।।]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[িাটন তরাগান তজাশ




        উপকরণঃ

        খামসর  াাংস ১ মকজে,


        লবন ২ চা চা চ,

         িক েই ১/২ কাপ,


        সরজের মতল ১/২ কাপ,

        মতেপাতা ২ িা,


        কাজলা এলাচ ২ মপস,

        সবুে এলাচ ৫ মপস,


         লাং ৬ িা,


        োরমচমন ৩ িুকরা,

                   ু
        মপয়াোঁে কমচ ১ কাপ,

        রসুন বািা ১ মিমবল চা চ,

        আোবািা ১ মিমবল চা চ,


        লাল মরচ গুোোঁ ২ মিমবল চা চ,


        ম  মর গুো ১ চা চা চ।

         প্রণাল ঃ



                                                                                                              ু
         কোইজত মতল গর  কজর সব আস্ত  শলা গুজলা মেজত হজব। সুগ঩ৎধ মবর হজল মপয়াোঁে কমচ
        মেজয় ভােজত হজব। মপয়াোঁে হালকা ভাো হজল আো – রসুনবািা মেজয়  শলা কোজত হজব।


         াাংস মেজয় একিু মভজে লবন ও  মরচগুো মেজয়  াাংস কোজত হজব। মেজক রাপ৏না করজত হজব।

         াাংস কজে চারপাজশ মতল মবর হজল িকেই অল্প পামন মেজয়  াাংজস মেজল মেজত হজব।  াাংস


        মসদ্ধ হওয়া পে ণি অজপিা করজত হজব।  াাংস হজয় মগজল ম  মর গুো মছটিজয় না াজত হজব।।



        তানজে া আল]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[জাবলপবল বপঠা
                   ু




        উপকরন্ঃ


        মবমপ৏নচাউজলর গুো-- ৪ কাপ


        মকাোজনা নামরজকল-- ২কাপ

        মচমন বা পািামল গুে -- ১কাপ


        (মে মে ন ম টষ্ট খান মত ন মেজবন)

        লবন --পমর ান  ত।


        পামন -- চাউজলর গুো  াখাজত ো লাগজব।



        প্রস্তুত প্রনালী্ঃ


        ১জকজে মবমপ৏নচাউল ধুজয় সা ানি পামন মেজয় ৩০ম মনি মভজেজয় রাখুন। ৩০ম মনি পর একিা


        ঝােমেজত মনন, এবাং পামন ঝরজত মেন। স্তুপ কজর না মরজখ ঝােমরজত মবমলজয় মেন। মফজনর

                                                       ু
        মনজচ রাখুন। িন্টা খাজনক পর চাউল মকছিা শুকনা ঝরঝজর হজয় মগজল মেন্ডাজর গুো কজর

        মনন। একিা বে োলায় চাউজলর গুো মনন, তাজত লবন মেন, সা ানি পামনর মছিা মেজয়  াখুন (

        ভাপামপোর গুমেরর  ত কজর )। একিা চালমন বা প্লামেজকর ঝােমরজত  াখাজনা েলাহওয়া গুো

                                            ু
        গুমল স ানভাজব মচজলমনন। মকছ স য় এভাজবই রাখুন।

                                                চুলায় একিা ননটষ্টক মপন মেন তাজত মকাোজনা নামরজকল


                                                 ও  মচমন  মেন  মলা   াঝামর  আোঁজচ  ভােুন।  মচমন  গজল

                                                  নামরজকজলর  সাজে  ম জশ  োজব।  একিু  আো  আো  হজল


                                                  নাম জয় োন্ডা করুন।

                                                   এবার  চুলার  আোঁচ   াঝামর  কজর  তাজত  একিা  ননটষ্টক


                                                    তাওয়া  বা  মপন  বসান।  হালকা  গর   হজল  আধাকাপ

                                                     চাউজলর গুো তাজত মগালকজর মবমছজয় মেন। এই স য়


                                                      চুলার আোঁচ একিু কম জয় মেজবন। চাউজলর গুো একিু

                                          স্বচ্ছ হজয়এজল নামরজকজলর পুর মেন (আপনার পছন্দ ত) মপোর]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[একপাজস। খামল আাংশ উটেজয় নামরজকজলর উপর মেজক মেন মস্পচুলা বা চা চ মেজয় মচজপ  ুখ


        ব঩ৎধ  কজর  মেন।  একপাস  হজয়জগজল  আপর  পাস  উজে  মেন।  ততমরহজয়জগল  োরুন  স্বাজের

        োলপুমল মপো।




        #ফাজরােী

        ফারজেয়ানা হ াক্তাজের।


        এিা আ ার নানুর মরজসমপ।




        এিা ১৯৭৭ এর কো। মবজয়র আজগ মত ন মকান রাপ৏নাই োনতা  না। ভাত আর মড  ভাজে

        ছাো। আ ার বর এইসব মপো খুব পছন্দ কজর। মবজয়র ছয় াস পর েখন ওনার ক  ণহৎথল মেজক

                                    ু
        মেশ মবোজত এলা  নান বামেজত।তখন নানুর কাজছ মেজক এই মপোর মরজসমপ মশজখমছ আজরা

        নানা রকজ রর রাপ৏নার সাজে।]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Rhapsody of Her Eye's



        Fathmee Zubair Galib

                                                      Device : Nikon D 7100

                                                       Lens: Nikon 50mm-1:1.8D
                                                                Nikkor AF-S85mm-1:1.8G

                                                                Nikkor AF-S 24-70mm-1:2.8G]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[s]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Device : Nikon D7100


                                                                             Lens: Nikon 50mm-1:1.8D






































                    Device : Canon 5D Mark II


                    Lens: Canon 70-200mm-1:2.8]]></page></pages></Search>